var words = 
[
    {
        "question": "أَبَابِيلَ",
        "answer": "(in) flocks",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 8,
        "tlit": "abābīla",
        "frequency": "3",
        "surahnum": "105",
        "ayahnum": "3",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَرْسَلَ عَلَيْهِمْ طَيْرًا أَبَابِيلَ",
        "rootWord": "أ ب ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَبَابِيل",
        "waznEnglish": "flocks",
        "waznTlit": "abābīl",
        "waznType": "Adjective"
    },
    {
        "question": "مَأْكُولٍ",
        "answer": "eaten up",
        "pcklId": "108",
        "rootWordId": 54,
        "tlit": "makūlin",
        "frequency": "109",
        "surahnum": "105",
        "ayahnum": "5",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " فَجَعَلَهُمْ كَعَصْفٍ مَأْكُولٍ",
        "rootWord": "أ ك ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "مَّأْكُول",
        "waznEnglish": "that which is eaten",
        "waznTlit": "makūl",
        "waznType": "Passive participle"
    },
    {
        "question": "يَجْعَلْ",
        "answer": "He make",
        "pcklId": "338",
        "rootWordId": 249,
        "tlit": "yajʿal",
        "frequency": "346",
        "surahnum": "105",
        "ayahnum": "2",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " أَلَمْ يَجْعَلْ كَيْدَهُمْ فِي تَضْلِيلٍ",
        "rootWord": "ج ع ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "جَعَلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to make",
        "waznTlit": "jaʿala",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَجَعَلَهُمْ",
        "answer": "Then He made them",
        "pcklId": "339",
        "rootWordId": 249,
        "tlit": "fajaʿalahum",
        "frequency": "346",
        "surahnum": "105",
        "ayahnum": "5",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " فَجَعَلَهُمْ كَعَصْفٍ مَأْكُولٍ",
        "rootWord": "ج ع ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "جَعَلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to make",
        "waznTlit": "jaʿala",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "بِحِجَارَةٍ",
        "answer": "with stones",
        "pcklId": "9",
        "rootWordId": 294,
        "tlit": "biḥijāratin",
        "frequency": "21",
        "surahnum": "105",
        "ayahnum": "4",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " تَرْمِيهِمْ بِحِجَارَةٍ مِنْ سِجِّيلٍ",
        "rootWord": "ح ج ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "حِجَارَة",
        "waznEnglish": "and [the] stones",
        "waznTlit": "ḥijārat",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "تَرَ",
        "answer": "you seen",
        "pcklId": "268",
        "rootWordId": 523,
        "tlit": "tara",
        "frequency": "328",
        "surahnum": "105",
        "ayahnum": "1",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " أَلَمْ تَرَ كَيْفَ فَعَلَ رَبُّكَ بِأَصْحَابِ الْفِيلِ",
        "rootWord": "ر أ ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَءَا",
        "waznEnglish": "to see",
        "waznTlit": "raā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "رَبُّكَ",
        "answer": "your Lord",
        "pcklId": "969",
        "rootWordId": 524,
        "tlit": "rabbuka",
        "frequency": "980",
        "surahnum": "105",
        "ayahnum": "1",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " أَلَمْ تَرَ كَيْفَ فَعَلَ رَبُّكَ بِأَصْحَابِ الْفِيلِ",
        "rootWord": "ر ب ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "رَبّ",
        "waznEnglish": "the Lord",
        "waznTlit": "rabb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "وَأَرْسَلَ",
        "answer": "And He sent",
        "pcklId": "129",
        "rootWordId": 555,
        "tlit": "wa-arsala",
        "frequency": "513",
        "surahnum": "105",
        "ayahnum": "3",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَرْسَلَ عَلَيْهِمْ طَيْرًا أَبَابِيلَ",
        "rootWord": "ر س ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَرْسَلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to send",
        "waznTlit": "arsala",
        "waznType": "Verb (form IV)"
    },
    {
        "question": "تَرْمِيهِمْ",
        "answer": "Striking them",
        "pcklId": "8",
        "rootWordId": 593,
        "tlit": "tarmīhim",
        "frequency": "9",
        "surahnum": "105",
        "ayahnum": "4",
        "wordnum": "1",
        "arabicAyah": " تَرْمِيهِمْ بِحِجَارَةٍ مِنْ سِجِّيلٍ",
        "rootWord": "ر م ي",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ر م ي",
        "waznEnglish": "to throw, to accuse",
        "waznTlit": "rā mīm yā",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "سِجِّيلٍ",
        "answer": "baked clay",
        "pcklId": "3",
        "rootWordId": 661,
        "tlit": "sijjīlin",
        "frequency": "4",
        "surahnum": "105",
        "ayahnum": "4",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " تَرْمِيهِمْ بِحِجَارَةٍ مِنْ سِجِّيلٍ",
        "rootWord": "س ج ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "سِجِّيل",
        "waznEnglish": "(of) a scroll",
        "waznTlit": "sijjīl",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "بِأَصْحَابِ",
        "answer": "with (the) Companions",
        "pcklId": "80",
        "rootWordId": 822,
        "tlit": "bi-aṣḥābi",
        "frequency": "97",
        "surahnum": "105",
        "ayahnum": "1",
        "wordnum": "6",
        "arabicAyah": " أَلَمْ تَرَ كَيْفَ فَعَلَ رَبُّكَ بِأَصْحَابِ الْفِيلِ",
        "rootWord": "ص ح ب",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "أَصْحَٰب",
        "waznEnglish": "can be protected",
        "waznTlit": "aṣḥāb",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "تَضْلِيلٍ",
        "answer": "astray",
        "pcklId": "187",
        "rootWordId": 891,
        "tlit": "taḍlīlin",
        "frequency": "191",
        "surahnum": "105",
        "ayahnum": "2",
        "wordnum": "5",
        "arabicAyah": " أَلَمْ يَجْعَلْ كَيْدَهُمْ فِي تَضْلِيلٍ",
        "rootWord": "ض ل ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "تَضْلِيل",
        "waznEnglish": "he went astray (from)",
        "waznTlit": "taḍlīl",
        "waznType": "Verbal noun (form II)"
    },
    {
        "question": "طَيْرًا",
        "answer": "birds",
        "pcklId": "22",
        "rootWordId": 937,
        "tlit": "ṭayran",
        "frequency": "29",
        "surahnum": "105",
        "ayahnum": "3",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " وَأَرْسَلَ عَلَيْهِمْ طَيْرًا أَبَابِيلَ",
        "rootWord": "ط ي ر",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "طَيْر",
        "waznEnglish": "(that) flies",
        "waznTlit": "ṭayr",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "كَعَصْفٍ",
        "answer": "like straw",
        "pcklId": "2",
        "rootWordId": 994,
        "tlit": "kaʿaṣfin",
        "frequency": "7",
        "surahnum": "105",
        "ayahnum": "5",
        "wordnum": "2",
        "arabicAyah": " فَجَعَلَهُمْ كَعَصْفٍ مَأْكُولٍ",
        "rootWord": "ع ص ف",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "عَصْف",
        "waznEnglish": "forcefully",
        "waznTlit": "ʿaṣf",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "فَعَلَ",
        "answer": "dealt",
        "pcklId": "87",
        "rootWordId": 1143,
        "tlit": "faʿala",
        "frequency": "108",
        "surahnum": "105",
        "ayahnum": "1",
        "wordnum": "4",
        "arabicAyah": " أَلَمْ تَرَ كَيْفَ فَعَلَ رَبُّكَ بِأَصْحَابِ الْفِيلِ",
        "rootWord": "ف ع ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "فَعَلَ",
        "waznEnglish": "to do",
        "waznTlit": "faʿala",
        "waznType": "Verb (form I)"
    },
    {
        "question": "الْفِيلِ",
        "answer": "(of the) Elephant",
        "pcklId": "0",
        "rootWordId": 1169,
        "tlit": "l-fīli",
        "frequency": "1",
        "surahnum": "105",
        "ayahnum": "1",
        "wordnum": "7",
        "arabicAyah": " أَلَمْ تَرَ كَيْفَ فَعَلَ رَبُّكَ بِأَصْحَابِ الْفِيلِ",
        "rootWord": "ف ي ل",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ف ي ل",
        "waznEnglish": "(of the) Elephant",
        "waznTlit": "fā yā lām",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "كَيْدَهُمْ",
        "answer": "their plan",
        "pcklId": "33",
        "rootWordId": 1307,
        "tlit": "kaydahum",
        "frequency": "35",
        "surahnum": "105",
        "ayahnum": "2",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " أَلَمْ يَجْعَلْ كَيْدَهُمْ فِي تَضْلِيلٍ",
        "rootWord": "ك ي د",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "كَيْد",
        "waznEnglish": "scheme against me",
        "waznTlit": "kayd",
        "waznType": "Noun"
    },
    {
        "question": "كَيْفَ",
        "answer": "how",
        "pcklId": "79",
        "rootWordId": 1308,
        "tlit": "kayfa",
        "frequency": "83",
        "surahnum": "105",
        "ayahnum": "1",
        "wordnum": "3",
        "arabicAyah": " أَلَمْ تَرَ كَيْفَ فَعَلَ رَبُّكَ بِأَصْحَابِ الْفِيلِ",
        "rootWord": "ك ي ف",
        "rootWordType": "triliteral root",
        "wazn": "ك ي ف",
        "waznEnglish": "How",
        "waznTlit": "kāf yā fā",
        "waznType": "Nominal (Interogative particle)"
    }
]; 
export default words;